人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯 雙語字幕
■
僅供學習 禁止盈利
更多影視更新
www.YYeTs.com
翻譯：伊森先生    Jellobird    愚公移山
■
翻譯：情瘦醫生    維京人Astrid    薄荷小瑾
女貞路
校對：somehacker    後期：Sung1219
我早該料到你會來  麥格教授
I should've known that you would be here, Professor McGonagall.
晚上好  鄧布利多教授
Good evening, Professor Dumbledore.
傳聞是真的嗎  阿布思
Are the rumors true, Albus?
很遺憾  是的  教授  好的壞的都是
I'm afraid so, professor. The good and the bad.
-那孩子呢  -海格會帶他來
- And the boy? - Hagrid is bringing him.
這麼重要的事情交給海格合適嗎
Is it wise to trust Hagrid with something so important?
教授  我可以把性命托付給他
Professor, I would trust Hagrid with my life.
你們好  鄧布利多教授  麥格教授
Professor Dumbledore, sir. Professor McGonagall.
-沒出岔子吧  海格  -沒有  教授
- No problems, I trust, Hagrid? - No, sir.
小傢伙在布里斯托上空睡著了
Little tyke fell asleep as we were flying over Bristol.
別吵醒他
Try not to wake him.
給您
There you go.
你覺得把孩子交給這些人安全嗎  阿布思
Albus, do you really think it's safe, leaving him with these people?
我觀察他們一天了  他們真是差勁的麻瓜
I've watched them all day. They're the worst sort of Muggles.
-他們真的是  -他唯一的親人了
- They really are  - The only family he has.
他的名字在我們的世界將會無人不知
He'll be famous. There won't be a child in our world who doesn't know his name.
沒錯
Exactly.
所以最好讓他遠離這種影響
He's far better off growing up away from all of that.
直到他準備好
Until he's ready.
好了  好了  海格  又不是永別
There, there, Hagrid. It's not really goodbye, after all.
德斯禮夫婦親啟
薩堸p小惠金區女貞路4號
祝你好運
Good luck
哈利·波特
Harry Potter.
與魔法石
起床  快起床
Up. Get up!
快點
Now!
醒醒  表弟  去動物園啦
Wake up, cousin! We're going to the zoo!
-你終於來啦  小壽星  -生日快樂  兒子
- Here he comes, the birthday boy. - Happy birthday, son.
快做早飯  別再把什麼東西點著了
Why don't you just cook the breakfast and try not to burn anything.
-好的  佩妮阿姨  -今天一定要事事順利
- Yes, Aunt Petunia. - I want everything to be perfect
因為是乖兒子的生日
for my Dudley's special day!
-快點  給我倒咖啡  -好的  弗農姨父
- Hurry up! Bring my coffee, boy. - Yes, Uncle Vernon.
是不是很棒啊  寶貝
Aren't they wonderful, darling?
-有幾件禮物  -36件  你自己數數看
- How many are there? - 36. Counted them myself.
36件  我去年就有37件
36?! But last year I had 37!
-可是有幾件比去年的大多了  -我才不管
- But some are bigger than last year's. - I don't care!
我們就這麼辦吧
This is what we're going to do.
一會再給你買兩件新禮物  怎麼樣  心肝兒
We're going to buy you two new presents. How's that, pumpkin?
這好天氣去動物園太棒了
It should be a lovely day at the zoo.
我真是無比的期待
I'm really looking forward to it.
我警告你  小子
I'm warning you now, boy.
今天再給我搞怪  不管是什麼
Any funny business, any at all...
我就一個禮拜不給你飯吃
and you won't have any meals for a week.
上車
Get in.
爬蟲類館
快讓它動
Make it move.
快動
Move!
-動啊  -他睡著了
- Move! - He's asleep!
沒意思
He's boring.
不好意思
Sorry about him.
他根本不理解你  整天躺著
He doesn't understand what it's like, lying there day after day
看著人們把醜臉貼上來
watching people press their ugly faces in on you.
你能聽到我說話
Can you hear me?
只是  以前我從沒和蛇說過話
It's just, I've never talked to a snake before.
你呢
Do you?
你常常和人交談嗎
Do you talk to people often?
你從緬甸來  對吧  那埵n玩嗎
You're from Burma, aren't you? Was it nice there?
你想念你的家人嗎
Do you miss your family?
園內孵育
明白了  我也一樣  從沒見過父母
I see. That's me as well. I never knew my parents either.
媽  爸  快來看這蛇
Mummy, Dad, you won't believe what this snake is doing!
謝謝
Thanks.
願意效勞
Anytime.
有蛇啊
Snake!
媽媽  媽媽  快救我
Mum! Mummy! Help me!
我的心肝寶貝  你怎麼進去的
My darling boy! How did you get in there?
誰幹的  你怎麼進去的  蛇還在堶捷鄃NWho did this? How did you get in there? Is there a snake?
沒事的  寶貝兒子
It's all right, sweetheart.
我來給你換了濕衣服
We'll get you out of these cold clothes.
-你幹了什麼  -我發誓  我不知道
- What happened? - I swear, I don't know!
玻璃本來好好的  突然不見了  像魔法一樣
The glass was there and then it was gone, like magic.
根本沒有什麼魔法
There's no such thing as magic.
快去取郵件  趕緊
Go get the post. Go!
哈利·波特先生親啟
薩堸p小惠金區女貞路4號樓梯下碗櫥內
喔  瑪姬吃了個壞油螺生病了
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
-爸爸  看  哈利有封信  -那是我的
- Dad, look! Harry's got a letter! - It's mine!
你的  誰會給你寫信啊
Yours? Who'd be writing to you?
我看你怎麼收信
No more mail through this letterbox.
祝你工作愉快  老公
Have a lovely day at the office, dear.
去去  快滾
Shoo! Go on.
星期天真是好啊
Fine day, Sunday.
依我看  一周最好的就是今天  達力  為什麼呢
In my opinion, best day of the week. Why is that, Dudley?
-因為星期天不送信嗎  -被你說中了  哈利
- Because there's no post on Sundays? - Right you are, Harry!
星期天沒人送信
No post on Sunday.
沒有該死的信了  沒了
No blasted letters today! No, sir.
一封該死的信也沒有  沒有
Not one single bloody letter. Not one!
沒那些該死的  噁心的
No, sir, not one blasted, miserable...
快停下來
Make it stop, please!
停下來
Stop it!
媽媽  發生什麼事了
Mummy, what's happening?
給我  把那封信給我
Give me that! Give me that letter!
放開我
Get off!
那是我的信  放開我
They're my letters! Let go of me!
我受夠了  我們離開這
That's it! We're going away!
走的遠遠的  誰也找不到
Far away, where they can't find us!
爸爸是不是瘋了
Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he?
哈利  生日快樂
許個願吧  哈利
Make a wish, Harry.
誰在外面
Who's there?
真不好意思
Sorry about that.
我要求你馬上離開  你這是私闖民宅
I demand that you leave at once. You are breaking and entering.
閉嘴吧  德斯禮  你這個老混蛋
Dry up, Dursley, you great prune.
上次見你時你還是個小不點  哈利
I haven't seen you since you was a baby, Harry.
你比我想像中長得結實嘛
You're a bit more along than I expected.
尤其是那小肚皮
Particularly in the middle.
我不是哈利
I'm not Harry.
-我才是  -當然是你啦
- I am. - Well, of course you are.
有東西給你
Got something for you.
我不小心坐了一下  但應該還是挺好吃的
Afraid I sat on it, but I imagine it'll taste fine just the same.
我自己烤的  還寫了字
Baked it myself, words and all.
謝謝你
Thank you.
11歲生日可不是每天都有的  對吧
It's not every day your young man turns 11, is it?
不好意思  你是哪位
Excuse me, but who are you?
魯伯·海格  霍格沃茲的場地和鑰匙保管員
Rubeus Hagrid, Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts.
-霍格沃茲你總知道吧  -對不起  我不知道
- Of course, you know about Hogwarts. - Sorry, no.
你從沒想過你爸媽在哪兒學會的嗎
Didn't you ever wonder where your mum and dad learned it all?
學會什麼
Learned what?
你是個巫師  哈利
You're a wizard, Harry.
-我是什麼  -巫師
- I'm a what? - A wizard.
還是個厲害巫師  只要你好好學習
A good one, I'd wager, once you're trained up.
我想你搞錯了  我是說
No, you've made a mistake. I mean
我怎麼會是巫師
I can't be a wizard.
我只是哈利  只是個小男孩
I mean, I'm just Harry. Just Harry.
好吧  哈利  你生氣或害怕的時候
Well, Just Harry, did you ever make anything happen?
有沒有做出過你自己也無法解釋的事情
Anything you couldn't explain, when you were angry or scared?
親愛的波特先生  很榮幸通知您
"Dear Mr. Potter, We are pleased to accept you
您已被霍格沃茲魔法學校錄取
at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. "
他才不會去
He will not be going I tell you!
在收留他的那天  我們就發誓要阻止這一切
We swore when we took him that we'd put a stop to all this rubbish.
你們知道  怎麼從來沒告訴過我
You knew? You knew all along and you never told me?
我們當然知道  你也是那種貨色
Of course we knew. How could you not be?
就像我那姐姐一個樣子
My perfect sister being who she was.
我爸媽在她收到信那天多麼自豪
My mother and father were so proud the day she got her letter.
我們家出了個女巫  真是太棒了
"We have a witch in the family. Isn't it wonderful?"
只有我才知道她的底細
I was the only one to see her for what she was.
她是個怪胎
A freak!
然後她認識了那個波特  又有了你
Then she met that Potter, and then she had you
我就知道你也是那種貨色
and I knew you would be the same.
一樣奇怪  也是怪胎
Just as strange, just as abnormal.
然後她就把自己炸死了  我們只能收留你
And then she went and got herself blown up, and we got landed with you.
炸死  你說我爸媽死於車禍
Blown up? You told me my parents died in a car crash.
什麼車禍  車禍能殺了莉莉和詹姆斯嗎
A car crash? A car crash killed Lily and James Potter?
-總得編個理由吧  -這是侮辱  這是誹謗
- We had to say something. - It's an outrage! A scandal!
他才不會去呢
He'll not be going.
你個大塊頭麻瓜想阻止嗎
And I suppose a great Muggle like you is going to stop him, are you?
什麼麻瓜
Muggle?
不會魔法的人  這孩子剛出生就注定要去
Non-magic folk. This boy's had his name down since he were born.
他要去最好的魔法學校
He's going to the finest school of witchcraft and wizardry.
現在的校長
He'll be under the finest
是霍格沃茲有史以來最好的  阿布思·鄧布利多
headmaster Hogwarts has seen, Albus Dumbledore.
我才不會付錢讓一個老糊塗去教他變戲法呢
I will not pay to have a crackpot old fool teach him magic tricks.
不許你在我面前
Never insult Albus Dumbledore
侮辱鄧布利多
in front of me.
請不要告訴霍格沃茲的任何人
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone at Hogwarts about that.
-他們禁止我使用魔法  -沒問題
- I'm not allowed to do magic. - Okay.
我們要遲到了  得快走
We're a bit behind schedule. Best be off.
當然了  除非你想留在這
Unless you'd rather stay, of course.
所有的學生都必須準備
All students must be equipped with
一個2號大坩堝
one standard size 2 pewter cauldron
還可以自帶
and may bring, if they desire,
一隻貓頭鷹  貓或是蟾蜍
either an owl, a cat or a toad.
在倫敦能找到這些東西嗎
Can we find all this in London?
只要你找對地方
If you know where to go.
你來啦  海格  還是老樣子嗎
Ah, Hagrid! The usual, I presume?
謝了  湯姆  今天要替霍格沃茲辦正事
No, thanks, Tom. I'm on official Hogwarts business.
在幫小哈利買學習用品呢
Just helping Harry buy his school supplies.
我的老天爺  是哈利·波特
Bless my soul. It's Harry Potter!
歡迎回來  波特先生  歡迎
Welcome back, Mr. Potter. Welcome back.
我是桃麗絲·克羅克福德  見到你太榮幸了
Doris Crockford. I can't believe I'm meeting you at last.
哈利·波特  我的榮幸之情無法言喻
Harry Potter. Can't tell you how pleased I am to meet you.
你好  教授  差點沒看到您
Hello, professor. I didn't see you.
哈利  這是奇洛教授
Harry, this is Professor Quirrell.
他在霍格沃茲教黑魔法防禦術
He will be teaching your Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts.
很高興見到你
Oh, nice to meet you.
奇妙又可怕的學科
Fearfully fascinating subject.
不過你用不著學  是吧
Not that you need it, eh, Potter?
好吧  該走了  好多東西要買
Yes, well, must be going now. Lots to buy.
再見
Goodbye.
-看見沒  波特  你很出名  -但是為什麼
- See, Harry? You're famous. - But why am I famous?
大家為什麼都知道我是誰
All those people back there, how is it they know who I am?
由我來告訴你可能不太合適  哈利
I'm not sure I'm the right person to tell you that.
哈利  歡迎來到對角巷
Welcome, Harry, to Diagon Alley.
這堨i以買鵝毛筆和墨水
Here, you get your quills and ink.
那邊  可以買到搗鼓魔法的各種小玩意
Over there, all your bits and bobs for doing wizardry.
這可是世界級的飛天掃把
It's a world-class racing broom.
快看  是最新的光輪2000
Look at it! The new Nimbus 2000!
這是最快的掃帚了
It's the fastest model yet.
可是我拿什麼買呢 海格  我又沒有錢
But Hagrid, how am I to pay for all this? I haven't any money.
你的錢在那  古靈閣  巫師銀行
There's your money. Gringotts, the wizard bank.
要存東西  那堻怞w全  當然除了霍格沃茲
Ain't no safer place, not one. Except perhaps Hogwarts.
海格  那些是什麼東西
Hagrid, what exactly are these things?
他們是妖精  哈利
They're goblins, Harry.
妖精很聰明  但卻不怎麼友善
Clever as they come, goblins, but not the most friendly of beasts.
最好跟緊我
Best stay close.
哈利·波特先生想取一些錢
Mr. Harry Potter wishes to make a withdrawal.
那麼  哈利·波特先生帶鑰匙了嗎
And does Mr. Harry Potter have his key?
等一下  我看看放哪了
Wait a minute. Got it here somewhere.
在這  這小玩意
Ha! There's the little devil.
還有件事
And there's something else as well.
鄧布利多教授給了我這個
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
最高機密
致對角巷  古靈閣銀行  首席妖精
是在那個金庫的那個東西
It's about You-Know-What in vault you-know-which.
那好吧
Very well.
687號金庫
Vault 687.
請給我燈
Lamp, please.
鑰匙
Key, please.
你不會以為你父母什麼都不給你留吧
Did you think your parents would leave you with nothing, did you?
-713號金庫  -堶惇O什麼  海格
- Vault 713. - What's in there, Hagrid?
無可奉告  霍格沃茲公務  最高機密
Can't tell you. Hogwarts business. Very secret.
退後
Stand back.
這事最好不要告訴任何人  哈利
Best not to mention this to anyone, Harry.
我還需要  一根魔杖
I still need a wand.
魔杖的話  去奧利凡德吧  最好的魔杖店
A wand? You want Ollivanders. There ain't no place better.
你去那媔R吧  然後等著
Why don't you run along there and wait.
我還有別的事  不會太久
I just got one more thing I got to do. It won't be long.
有人嗎
Hello?
終於見到您了  波特先生
I wondered when I'd be seeing you, Mr. Potter.
當年你的父母
It seems only yesterday
就是在這買的第一根魔杖
...that your mother and father
彷彿是昨天的事
were in here buying their first wands.
試試這根
Here we are.
揮一下試試
Give it a wave.
看來這根不行
Apparently not.
也許
Perhaps...
這根能行
...this.
不  不  絕對不行  沒關係
No, no, definitely not. No matter.
興許是這根
I wonder...
奇妙
Curious.
真是太奇妙了
Very curious.
抱歉  什麼地方讓您覺得奇妙
Sorry, but what's curious?
我賣出的每一根魔杖我都記得  波特先生
I remember every wand I've ever sold, Mr. Potter.
碰巧這根魔杖
It so happens that the phoenix...
和另一根魔杖的杖芯
...whose tail feather resides in your wand, gave another feather.
是同一隻鳳凰身上的羽毛
Just one other.
奇妙之處在於這根魔杖竟選擇了你
It is curious that you should be destined for this wand...
因為它的兄弟給了你那道傷疤
...when its brother gave you that scar.
那根魔杖的主人是誰
And who owned that wand?
我們從不提起他的名字
We do not speak his name.
是魔杖選擇巫師  波特先生
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
原因向來無法解釋
It's not always clear why.
但我覺得
But I think it is clear...
你會成就一番大事業的
...that we can expect great things from you.
畢竟  連名字都不能提的那個人
After all, He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
也大有成就
...did great things.
儘管可怕
Terrible...
卻還是大事
...yes, but great.
哈利  哈利
Harry! Harry!
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
你還好嗎  哈利  怎麼不吭聲
You all right, Harry? You seem very quiet.
他殺了我父母  對不對
He killed my parents, didn't he?
給我留下這道傷疤的人
The one who gave me this.
你知道的  海格  你一定知道
You know, Hagrid. I know you do.
首先你要知道一件很重要的事
First, and understand this because it's very important:
巫師並不一定都是好人
Not all wizards are good.
有些巫師會變壞  幾年前
Some of them go bad. A few years ago...
有個巫師變得很壞很壞
...there was a wizard who went as bad as you can go.
他的名字叫伏...
And his name was V...
-他的名字叫伏... -你要不要寫下來
- His name was V... - Maybe if you wrote it down?
不了  我不會寫
No, I can't spell it.
-好吧  他叫伏地魔  -伏地魔
- All right, Voldemort. - Voldemort?
那是段黑暗的日子  哈利  太黑暗了
It was dark times, Harry. Dark times.
當時伏地魔聚集了一批爪牙
Voldemort started to gather some followers.
拉攏他們投靠邪惡勢力
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
反抗他的人都被殺害了
Anyone that stood up to him ended up dead.
你的父母奮起反抗
Your parents fought against him.
凡是他決意要殺的人  都活不下來
But nobody lived once he decided to kill them.
無人倖免
Nobody, not one.
除了你
Except you.
我嗎  伏地魔想要殺我嗎
Me? Voldemort tried to kill me?
沒錯  你額頭的傷疤可不尋常  哈利
Yes. That ain't no ordinary cut on your forehead, Harry.
只有咒語才能
A mark like that only comes
留下這種傷疤  而且是很邪惡的咒語
from being touched by a curse, an evil curse.
那伏...那個神秘人後來怎麼樣了
What happened to V...? To You-Know-Who?
有些人說他死了
Well, some say he died.
簡直是一派胡言
Codswallop, in my opinion.
我覺得他還活著
Nope, I reckon he's out there still...
只是沒力氣再回來了
...too tired to carry on.
但有一件事很肯定
But one thing's certain.
那天晚上你一定讓他元氣大傷
Something about you stumped him that night.
所以你才這麼有名  所以大家都認識你
That's why you're famous. That's why everybody knows your name.
你是大難不死的男孩
You're the boy who lived.
看什麼看
What are you looking at?
啊呀  已經這個點了
Blimey, is that the time?
抱歉  哈利  我得先走了
Sorry, Harry, I'm gonna have to leave you.
鄧布利多等著要他的...
Dumbledore will be wanting his...
他等著要見我
Well, he'll be wanting to see me.
你的火車還有10分鐘就開了
Your train leaves in 10 minutes.
這是你的票  把票收好  這很重要
Here's your ticket. Stick to your ticket, that's very important.
九又四分之三站台
"Platform 9 3/4"?
但是海格  票上寫錯了吧
But, Hagrid, there must be a mistake.
這媦g著九又四分之三站台
This says platform 9 3/4.
根本沒有這種站台  對吧
There's no such thing, is there?
抱歉
Sorry.
不好意思
Excuse me. Excuse me.
往左走
On your left.
請問九又四分之三站台在哪傜NCan you tell me where I might find platform 93/4?
九又四分之三  你在尋我開心嗎
9 3/4? Think you're being funny, do you?
每年都一樣  擠滿了麻瓜
It's the same every year, packed with Muggles.
-麻瓜  -九又四分之三站台  這邊
- Muggles? - Platform 9 3/4, this way.
好了  珀西  你先來
All right, Percy, you first.
弗雷德  你接著
Fred, you next.
他才不是弗雷德  我才是
He's not Fred, I am.
虧你還是媽媽  連你都分不清
Honestly, woman, you call yourself our mother?
抱歉  喬治
I'm sorry, George.
我開玩笑的  我是弗雷德
I'm only joking. I am Fred.
不好意思
Excuse me.
請問該怎麼
Could you tell me how to...?
怎麼去站台嗎  別擔心親愛的
How to get onto the platform? Not to worry, dear.
羅恩也是第一次去霍格沃茨
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as well.
你只要穿過
All you do is walk straight
9站台和10站台之間的那道牆就行了
at the wall between platforms 9 and 10.
-緊張的話就小跑過去  -祝你好運
- Best to run if you're nervous. - Good luck.
抱歉我能坐這媔  別的車廂都坐滿了
Excuse me. Do you mind? Everywhere else is full.
坐吧
Not at all.
我叫羅恩  羅恩·韋斯萊
I'm Ron, by the way. Ron Weasley.
我叫哈利  哈利·波特
I'm Harry. Harry Potter.
果然是真的
So... So it's true!
你真的有...
I mean, do you really have the...?
-有什麼  -那個傷疤
- The what? - The scar?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
帥呆了
Wicked!
要不要買點東西吃啊  孩子們
Anything off the trolley, dears?
不  謝了  我自己帶了
No, thanks. I'm all set.
我們全要了
We'll take the lot.
什麼是比比多味豆
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans?
就是各種口味都有
They mean every flavor.
有巧克力味的和薄荷味的
There's chocolate and peppermint and also...
還有菠菜  肝臟  牛肚味
...spinach, liver and tripe.
喬治說他有次吃到過鼻屎味的
George sweared he got a booger-flavored one once.
這是真的青蛙嗎
Are they real frogs?
這只是個咒語  主要是收集卡片用的
It's a spell. Besides, it's the cards you want.
每包附有一張著名巫師的卡片
Each pack's got a famous witch or wizard.
我已經收集了差不多500張了
I've got about 500 meself.
看好它
Watch it!
運氣真背  它們只能跳那一下
That's rotten luck. They've only got one good jump in them.
-我這張是鄧布利多  -我有六張了
- I've got Dumbledore! - I got about six of him.
他不見了
Hey, he's gone!
你總不能讓他一直呆在卡片堶惕a
You can't expect him to hang around all day, can you?
這個是斑斑  它真可憐  對吧
This is Scabbers. Pathetic, isn't he?
還好吧
A little.
弗雷德教了我一個咒語能把它變成黃色
Fred gave me a spell to turn him yellow.
-想見識下嗎  -好啊
- Want to see? - Yeah.
你們有看見一隻蟾蜍嗎
Has anyone seen a toad?
-納威把它給弄丟了  -沒見過
- A boy named Neville's lost one. - No.
你這是要施魔法嗎  讓我們來瞧瞧吧
Oh, are you doing magic? Let's see, then.
陽光  雛菊  甜奶油
Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow
把這只傻乎乎的肥老鼠變黃
Turn this stupid, fat rat yellow
你確定那個真的是咒語嗎
Are you sure that's a real spell?
看來不怎麼樣  是吧
Well, it's not very good, is it?
我也試過幾個簡單的咒語
I've only tried a few simple ones myself...
但都很有用
...but they've all worked for me.
舉個例子
For example:
修復一新
Oculus Reparo.
好多了  是不是
That's better, isn't it?
我的天  你是哈利·波特
Holy cricket, you're Harry Potter!
我叫赫敏·格蘭傑  你呢
I'm Hermione Granger. And you are...?
-我叫羅恩·韋斯萊  -幸會
- I'm Ron Weasley. - Pleasure.
你們倆最好把袍子都穿上
You two better change into robes.
我們快到了
I expect we'll be arriving soon.
你鼻子上有塊東西  你知道嗎
You've got dirt on your nose by the way. Did you know?
在這兒
Just there.
好了  新生  這邊走
Right, then. First years, this way, please!
來吧  新生  別害羞  快點快點
Come on, first years, don't be shy. Come on now, hurry up.
-你好  哈利  -你好  海格
- Hello, Harry. - Hi, Hagrid.
來  走這邊上船  快點  跟著我
Right, then. This way to the boats. Come on now, follow me.
帥呆了
Wicked.
歡迎來到霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts.
再過一會你們就會
Now, in a few moments you'll pass
走過這扇門和其他同學共聚一堂
through these doors and join your classmates.
但在你們到餐廳入席之前
But before you take your seats,
需要先為你們分派學院
you must be sorted into your houses.
分別有格蘭芬多  赫奇帕奇
They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff...
拉文克勞以及斯萊特林四個學院
...Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
在校期間  學院就是你們的家
While you're here, your house will be like your family.
你們的出色表現會為學院贏得加分
Your triumphs will earn you points.
而任何違規行為則會給學院減分
Any rule-breaking and you will lose points.
在年終時
At the end of the year,
獲最高分的學院可獲得學院杯
the house with the most points wins the house cup.
萊福
Trevor!
對不起
Sorry.
分院儀式馬上就要開始了
The Sorting Ceremony will begin momentarily.
火車上的傳聞果然是真的
It's true then, what they're saying on the train.
哈利·波特來霍格沃茨了
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
哈利·波特
Harry Potter?
這是克拉布和高爾
This is Crabbe and Goyle.
我是馬爾福
And I'm Malfoy.
德拉科·馬爾福
Draco Malfoy.
覺得我的名字很好笑是嗎
Think my name's funny, do you?
一眼就知道你是誰
I've no need to ask yours.
紅頭髮和舊長袍  想必是韋斯萊家的人
Red hair and a hand-me-down robe? You must be a Weasley.
你很快會發現有些巫師家族就是要高級些
You'll find out some wizarding families are better than others, Potter.
你不會想和這種貨色交朋友的
You don't want to go making friends with the wrong sort.
我倒是可以做你朋友
I can help you there.
我還分得清好壞  謝了
I think I can tell the wrong sort for myself, thanks.
一切準備就緒了  跟我走
We're ready for you now. Follow me.
這個屋頂不是真的
The ceiling isn't real.
它被施了魔咒所以看上去像夜空一樣
It's bewitched to look like the night sky.
我在《霍格沃茨  一段校史》媗爸儦L
I read about it in Hogwarts, A History.
請你們先在這媯扔茻NWill you wait along here, please?
現在  在我們開始前
Now, before we begin...
鄧布利多校長有幾句話要說
...Professor Dumbledore would like to say a few words.
我要先宣佈幾條新學期必須注意的事項
I have a few start-of-term notices I wish to announce.
一年級新生們請注意
The first years, please note...
禁林嚴禁學生進入
...that the Dark Forest is strictly forbidden to all students.
另外  我們的管理員
Also, our caretaker, Mr. Filch,
費爾奇先生要我提醒各位
has asked me to remind you...
如果不想死的很慘的話
...that the third-floor corridor is out of bounds...
就不要進入三樓右手邊的走廊
...to everyone who does not wish to die a most painful death.
謝謝
Thank you.
當我叫到你的名字時  請上前來
When I call your name, you will come forth.
我會給你戴上分院帽
I shall place the Sorting Hat on your head...
為你分派學院
...and you will be sorted into your houses.
赫敏·格蘭傑
Hermione Granger.
好了  放鬆
Oh, no. Okay, relax.
我告訴你  那人腦子絕對不正常
Mental, that one, I'm telling you.
好  好
Right, then. Right.
好了  格蘭芬多
Okay. Gryffindor!
德拉科·馬爾福
Draco Malfoy.
斯萊特林
Slytherin!
那些變壞的巫師都是斯萊特林出身的
Every wizard who went bad was in Slytherin.
蘇珊·博恩斯
Susan Bones.
哈利  怎麼了
Harry, what is it?
沒事  我沒事
Nothing. Nothing, I'm fine.
讓我想想
Let's see...
知道了  赫奇帕奇
I know! Hufflepuff!
羅恩·韋斯萊
Ronald Weasley.
又一個韋斯萊  我知道該把你分到哪了
Another Weasley! I know just what to do with you.
格蘭芬多
Gryffindor!
哈利·波特
Harry Potter.
難  著實難
Difficult, very difficult.
看得出很有勇氣  心地也不壞
Plenty of courage, I see. Not a bad mind, either.
而且很有天賦
There's talent, oh, yes.
急切的想要證明自己
And a thirst to prove yourself.
該把你分去哪個學院呢
But where to put you?
不去斯萊特林  不去斯萊特林
Not Slytherin, not Slytherin!
不去斯萊特林  你確定嗎
Not Slytherin, eh? Are you sure?
你能成大器  你的小腦瓜堻ˉg著呢
You could be great, you know. It's all here, in your head.
斯萊特林能幫你
And Slytherin will help you
走向輝煌  這是毫無疑問的
on the way to greatness, no doubt about that.
不要嘛  既然你決心已定
No? Well, if you're sure.
那就去
Better be...
格蘭芬多吧
...Gryffindor!
波特來這了
We got Potter!
請注意
Your attention, please.
宴會開始
Let the feast begin.
我是混血
I'm half and half.
我爸是麻瓜  我媽是女巫
Me dad's a Muggle. Mum's a witch.
我爸知道的時候嚇了一大跳
Bit of a nasty shock for him when he found out.
珀西  在和奇洛教授交談的那個老師是誰
Percy, who's that teacher talking to Professor Quirrell?
那是斯內普教授  斯萊特林的院長
Professor Snape, head of Slytherin house.
-他教什麼科目  -魔藥學
- What's he teach? - Potions.
但他最感興趣的是黑魔法防禦術
But he fancies the Dark Arts Defences.
他覬覦奇洛教授的位子很多年了
He's been after Quirrell's job for years.
大家好  你好啊
Hello! How are you?
歡迎來到格蘭芬多
Welcome to Gryffindor.
那是血人巴羅
It's the Bloody Baron!
你好  尼可拉斯爵士
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
暑期過得愉快嗎
Have a nice summer?
不開心  我想參加
Dismal. Once again, my request
無頭騎士狩獵  但又一次被拒絕了
to join the Headless Hunt has been denied.
我知道  你是「差點沒頭的尼克」
I know you. You're Nearly Headless Nick.
我更喜歡別人叫我尼古拉斯爵士
I prefer Sir Nicholas, if you don't mind.
差點沒頭  你怎麼能差點沒頭呢
"Nearly" Headless? How can you be nearly headless?
就像這樣
Like this.
格蘭芬多的同學請跟我來
Gryffindors, follow me, please.
大家跟上  謝謝
Keep up. Thank you.
拉文克勞的同學跟我來  這邊走
Ravenclaw, follow me. This way.
這是通往宿舍最直的路徑
This is the most direct path to the dormitories.
留神那些樓梯  它們隨時會變
Keep an eye on the staircases. They like to change.
請大家跟緊了  跟我走
Keep up, please, and follow me.
走快點  快點  快點
Quickly now, come on. Come on.
那幅畫在動
That picture's moving.
-看那一幅  -我想她喜歡你
- Look at that one. - I think she fancies you.
-快看啊  -那個女孩是誰
- Look! - Who's that girl?
歡迎來到霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts.
口令
Password?
龍渣
Caput Draconis.
大家跟我來  都跟上  快點
Follow me, everyone. Keep up. Quickly, come on.
在這媔隻X
Gather around here.
歡迎來到格蘭芬多的公共休息室
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
男生宿舍在樓上左手邊
Boys' dormitory is upstairs to the left.
女生的在樓上右手邊
Girls, the same on your right.
你們的行李已經被送到樓上了
Your belongings have already been brought up.
趕上了
Made it!
你能想像老麥格知道我們遲到了
Can you imagine the look
臉色會多難看嗎
on old McGonagall's face if we were late?
真是太厲害了
That was bloody brilliant!
多謝誇獎  韋斯萊先生
Thank you for that assessment.
或許把波特先生和你變成懷表
Perhaps it'd be more usefully
效果會更好些
if I transfigured Mr. Potter and yourself into a watch.
沒準你們就知道準時的意義了
Then one of you might be on time.
我們迷路了
We got lost.
那我該把你們變成地圖嘍
Then perhaps a map?
我相信找到你們自己的座位不需要地圖吧
I trust you don't need one to find your seats.
在我的課上
There will be no foolish
不准亂揮魔杖  不准亂唸咒語
wand-waving or silly incantations in this class.
就個人而言  我不指望你們中大多數人
As such, I don't expect many of you to appreciate...
能夠領會魔藥學中的技術與奧妙
...the subtle science and exact art that is potion-making.
不過  對那極少數
However, for those select few...
擁有資質的人
...who possess the predisposition...
我可以教你們如何迷惑人的心智
...I can teach you how to bewitch the mind...
囚禁人的感官
...and ensnare the senses.
我可以教你們如何罐藏名聲
I can tell you how to bottle fame
釀造榮譽
brew glory
甚至長生不死
and even put a stopper in death.
我還要重申
Then again,
也許有人覺得在霍格沃茨
maybe some of you have come to Hogwarts
仗著自己名氣大
in possession with abilities so formidable
就自信滿滿
that you feel confident enough...
覺得可以不專心聽講
...to not pay attention.
波特先生
Mr. Potter.
新生代的名人
Our new celebrity.
如果將水僊根粉末
What would I get if I added
加入艾草浸液中會得到什麼
root of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
你不知道  那我們換個問題
You don't know? Let's try again.
如果要找牛黃你應該從哪媯菑槙NWhere would you look if I asked you to find a bezoar?
我不知道  先生
I don't know, sir.
舟形烏頭和狼毒烏頭有什麼區別
What is the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane?
我不知道  先生
I don't know, sir.
真遺憾
Pity.
顯然  名聲不代表一切
Clearly, fame isn't everything...
對嗎  波特先生
...is it, Mr. Potter?
兔眼晶晶  豎琴幽幽
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum.
把這清水變美酒
Turn this water into rum
兔眼晶晶
Eye of rabbit...
西莫想對那杯水做什麼
What's Seamus going to do to that glass of water?
把它變成酒  昨天確實成功變出了淡茶
Turn it to rum. Actually managed a weak tea yesterday,
不過後來就...
before...
來郵件了
Mail's here.
我能借來看看嗎  謝謝
Can I borrow this? Thanks.
看啊  納威收到個記憶球
Look, Neville's got a Remembrall.
我在書媗爸儦L
I've read about those. The
如果你忘記了事情  煙會變成紅色
smoke turns red when you've forgotten something.
問題是  我不記得忘記了什麼事情
The problem is, I can't remember what I've forgotten.
有人非法闖入了古靈閣  聽這傜NSomebody broke into Gringotts. Listen.
相信是不明身份的黑巫師所為
"Believed to be the work of Dark wizards or witches unknown...
古靈閣的妖精承認有人闖入
...Gringotts goblins acknowledge
但是強調什麼都沒有失竊
the breach but insist nothing was taken.
遭竊的713號金庫
The vault in question, number 713,
在當天早些時候已空無一物
had been emptied earlier that same day. "
奇怪  我和海格去的就是這個金庫
That's odd. That's the vault Hagrid and I went to.
下午好  同學們
Good afternoon, class.
下午好  霍琦夫人
Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
下午好  阿曼達  下午好
Good afternoon, Amanda. Good afternoon.
歡迎參加你們的第一堂飛行課
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
你們還在等什麼  站到飛天掃帚左邊去
What are you waiting for? Step up to the left side of the broomstick.
來啊  動作快點
Come on now, hurry up.
把右手放在掃帚的正上方說  起
Stick your right hand over the broom and say, "Up. "
起
Up!
Up.
起
起  起
Up. Up!
帶點感情
With feeling.
閉嘴  哈利
Shut up, Harry.
拿到掃帚的同學  現在我要你們騎上去
Now, once you've got hold of your broom, I want you to mount it.
抓緊了  小心別滑下來
Grip it tight. You don't wanna be sliding off than.
當我吹響哨子
When I blow my whistle,
我要你們每一個人都用力蹬地
I want each of you to kick off from the ground, hard.
讓你們的掃帚飛起來  在空中停一會兒
Keep your broom steady, hover for a moment...
然後微微前傾  回到地面
...then lean forward slightly and touch back down.
注意我的哨音  3  2
On my whistle. Three, two...
隆巴頓先生
Mr. Longbottom.
-隆巴頓先生  -下去  下去
- Mr. Longbottom! - Down, down!
納威
Neville!
給我下來
Come back down this instant!
大家讓開
Everyone out of the way!
他沒事吧
Is he all right?
天哪  手腕骨折了
Oh, dear, it's a broken wrist.
可憐的孩子  來吧  站起來
Poor boy. Come on now, up you get.
在我送他去醫療室期間
Everyone has to Keep his feet firmly on the
你們都老老實實地呆在地上
ground while I take Mr. Longbottom to the hospital wing.
聽明白了嗎  不要讓我看到天上有掃帚
Understand? I see a single broom in the air...
否則直接開除
...the one riding it will find himself
連魁地奇的邊都碰不到
be expelled from Hogwarts before they can say Quidditch.
你們看到他的臉了嗎
Did you see his face?
如果他抓著這個
If he had squeezed this,
就會記得用屁股著陸
he'd have remembered to fall on his arse.
把它給我  馬爾福
Give it here, Malfoy.
不  我要藏起來讓隆巴頓去找
No. I think I'll leave it somewhere for Longbottom to find.
藏在屋頂上怎麼樣
How about on the roof?
怎麼了波特  夠不著嗎
What's the matter, Potter? Bit beyond your reach?
哈利別去  想想霍琦夫人說的話
Harry, no way! You heard what Madam Hooch said.
而且你還不知道怎麼飛
Besides, you don't know how to fly.
大傻瓜
What an idiot.
把它給我  不然我把你打下去
Give it here or I'll knock you off your broom!
你就這點本事嗎
Is that so?
要的話就自己去拿吧
Have it your way, then.
接得好  哈利
Nice going, Harry.
太棒了  哈利
That was wicked, Harry!
哈利·波特
Harry Potter!
跟我來
Follow me.
在這兒等著
You wait here.
對不起  奇洛教授
Professor Quirrell, excuse me.
能讓伍德出來一下嗎
Could I borrow Wood for a moment?
當然可以
Yes, of course.
波特  這位是奧利佛·伍德
Potter, this is Oliver Wood.
伍德  我給你找到個找球手
Wood, I have found you a Seeker.
你聽說了嗎
Have you heard?
哈利·波特成了格蘭芬多新的找球手
Harry Potter's the new Gryffindor Seeker.
我就知道他准行
I always knew he'd do well.
找球手  但是新生從來沒入選過院隊
Seeker? But first years never make the house teams.
你一定是最年輕的魁地奇選手
You must be the youngest Quidditch player in...
百年來最年輕的  麥格說的
A century, McGonagall says.
好樣的哈利  伍德都告訴我們了
Well done, Harry. Wood's just told us.
弗雷德和喬治也在隊上  他們是擊球手
Fred and George are on the team,too. Beaters.
我們的任務就是保護你不要被揍得太慘
Our job is to make sure you don't get bloodied up too bad.
打不了包票  魁地奇很野蠻
Can't make any promises. Rough game, Quidditch.
但是從來沒有死過人  偶爾有人會消失
But no one's died in years. Someone vanishes occasionally.
不過一兩個月後就會出現
But they'll turn up in a month or two.
去吧哈利  魁地奇很帶勁
Go on,Harry. Quidditch is great.
最好玩的運動  你也會成為最棒的
Best game there is, and you'll be great too.
我從來沒打過  要是出洋相了怎麼辦
I've never played. What if I make a fool of myself?
你才不會出洋相呢  有家族遺傳
You won't make a fool of yourself. It's in your blood.
找球手  詹姆·波特  1971年
你從沒說過你爸爸也是個找球手
You never told me your father was a Seeker too.
我不知道
I didn't know.
實話實說  這事挺玄乎的
I'm telling you, it's spooky.
關於你的事  赫敏知道的都比你多
She knows more about you than you do.
誰都比我多
Who doesn't?
出什麼事了
What's happening?
樓梯自己會變  記得嗎
The staircases change, remember?
-這邊走  -不然樓梯一會兒又要動了
- Let's go this way. - Before the staircase moves again.
有沒有人覺得我們走錯地方了
Does anybody feel like we shouldn't be here?
我們不該進來的
We're not supposed to be here.
三樓是禁地
This is the third floor. It's forbidden.
我們離開這兒
Let's go.
-是費爾奇的貓  -快跑
- It's Filch's cat! - Run!
快點  躲到那扇門後面去
Quick, let's hide through that door!
-門鎖上了  -我們完蛋了
- It's locked! - We're done for!
閃開
Move over!
阿拉霍洞開
Alohomora.
進來
Get in.
阿拉霍洞開?
Alohomora?
標準咒語手冊  第七章
Standard Book of Spells, chapter seven.
有人進來了嗎  親愛的
Anyone here, my sweet?
走吧
Come on.
-費爾奇走了  -他以為這門鎖著
- Filch is gone. - He thinks this door's locked.
-門是鎖著的  -肯定要鎖著
- It was locked. - And for good reason.
他們到底想幹嘛
What are they doing,
把這樣的東西關在學校傜Nkeeping a thing like that locked up in a school?
你眼睛是用來幹嘛的
You didn't use your eyes, aren't you?
沒看到它站在哪兒嗎
Didn't you see what it was standing on?
我沒看它的腳  我光顧著看它的頭了
I wasn't looking at its feet! I was preoccupied with its heads.
也許你沒有注意到  它有三個頭
Or maybe you didn't notice. There were three!
它站在一個暗門上  這肯定不是巧合
It was standing on a trap door. It wasn't there by accident.
-它在看守著什麼東西  -看守東西
- It's guarding something. - Guarding something?
沒錯  現在  如果你們倆不介意
That's right. Now, if you two don't mind,
我去睡了  免得你們兩個想出什麼妙計
I'm going to bed before either of you come up with another idea
害我們送命
to get us killed.
沒準更糟  被開除
Or worse, expelled.
她哪個更糟都分不清嗎
She needs to sort out her priorities.
魁地奇很簡單  每支隊伍有7個隊員
Quidditch is easy to understand. Each team has seven players.
3個追球手  2個擊球手
Three Chasers, two Beaters,
1個守門員和1個找球手  就是你
one Keeper and a Seeker. That's you.
一共有3種球  這種叫鬼飛球
There are three kinds of balls. This one's called the Quaffle.
追球手手持鬼飛球
The Chasers handle the Quaffle
把它扔進其中一個鐵環
and try to put it through one of those hoops.
而我作為守門員要守住鐵環  明白了嗎
The Keeper, that's me, defends the hoops. With me so far?
明白了  那這些是什麼
I think so. What are those?
你拿好這個
You better take this.
小心點  它回來了
Careful now, it's coming back.
幹得不錯  波特
Not bad, Potter.
你做擊球手也不賴
You'd make a fair Beater.
那到底是什麼
What was that?
遊走球  淘氣的小傢伙
Bludger. Nasty little buggers.
不過你是個找球手
But you are a Seeker.
你唯一要關心的是這個球
The only thing I want you to worry about is this.
金色飛賊
The Golden Snitch.
-我喜歡這顆球  -你沒嘗過它的厲害
- I like this ball. - You like it now.
等著瞧  它飛得超快  快得都沒影了
Just wait. It's wicked fast and damn near impossible to see.
我該怎麼做
What do I do with it?
趕在對方的找球手之前抓住它
You catch it. Before the other team's Seeker.
抓到它  比賽就結束了
You catch this, the game's over.
抓到它  波特  我們就贏了
You catch this, Potter, and we win.
懸停魔咒
One of a wizard's most rudimentary skills
是基礎咒語之一
is levitation...
就是讓物體飛起來
...or the ability to make objects fly.
你們都拿到羽毛了嗎  很好
Do you have your feathers? Good.
現在  不要忘記我們剛才練習過的
Now, don't forget the nice wrist movement
正確的魔杖揮舞手勢
we've been practicing.
一揮一抖  大家一起來
The swish and flick. Everyone.
一揮  再一抖
The swish and flick.
做得很好  再念動咒語
Good. Oh, and enunciate.
羽加迪姆  勒維奧薩  你們來試試
Wingardium Leviosa. Off you go, then.
羽加迪姆  勒維奧薩
Wingardium Leviosa.
不  停  停  停
No, stop, stop, stop!
你都要戳到別人的眼睛了
You're going to take someone's eye out.
而且你的咒語也念錯了
Besides, you're saying it wrong.
是勒維「奧」薩  而不是勒維奧「薩」
It's Leviosa, not Leviosar.
你那麼聰明  你倒是試試看啊  來啊
You do it then, if you're so clever. Go on, go on.
羽加迪姆  勒維奧薩
Wingardium Leviosa.
做得很好  大家看啊
Well done!  See here, everyone,
格蘭傑小姐做到了
Miss Granger's done it!
好極了
Splendid!
做得好  親愛的
Well done, dear.
教授  我想我們這兒還需要一根羽毛
I think we're going to need another feather over here, professor.
是勒維「奧」薩  而不是勒維奧「薩」
"It's Leviosa, not Leviosar. "
實話實說  她就是個噩夢
She's a nightmare, honestly!
難怪她交不到朋友
No wonder she hasn't got any friends.
我想她聽見了
I think she heard you.
赫敏去哪兒了
Where's Hermione?
帕瓦蒂說她一直待在浴室堣ㄔX來
Parvati said she wouldn't come out of the bathroom.
她在堶戚了一下午
She said that she'd been in there all afternoon, crying.
巨怪  在地下室
Troll in the dungeon!
地下室有巨怪
應該告訴你們一下
Thought you ought to know.
安靜
Silence!
請大家不要驚慌
Everyone will please not panic!
現在
Now
級長帶領各自學院的同學回到宿舍
prefects will lead their house back to the dormitories.
老師們跟我去地下室
Teachers will follow me to the dungeons.
格蘭芬多的同學  請跟上  保持警惕
Gryffindors, keep up, please, and stay alert.
巨怪怎麼會在學校出現
How could a troll get in?
肯定是被放進來的  巨怪都是大笨蛋
Not on its own. Trolls are really stupid.
也許是有人在惡作劇吧
Probably people playing jokes.
-幹嘛  -赫敏還不知情呢
- What? - Hermione! She doesn't know.
看來巨怪不在地下室
I think the troll's left the dungeon.
它要進女生盥洗室
It's going into the girls' bathroom.
赫敏  快跑
Hermione, move!
救命  救命
Help! Help!
這邊  大笨蛋
Hey, pea brain!
救命
Help!
別愣著不動啊
Do something!
-你讓我幹嘛  -隨便
- What? - Anything!
-快點  -一揮一抖
- Hurry up! - Swish and flick.
羽加迪姆  勒維奧薩
Wingardium Leviosa.
太帥了
Cool.
它死了嗎
Is it dead?
我看不像  是暈過去了
I don't think so. Just knocked out.
好噁心的鼻涕
Troll boogers.
天哪  都給我解釋清楚這是怎麼回事
Oh, my goodness! Explain yourselves, both of you!
事情是這樣的...
Well, what it is...
都是我的錯  麥格教授
It's my fault, Professor McGonagall.
格蘭傑小姐
Miss Granger?
我找巨怪來了
I went looking for the troll.
以為自己搞得定它
I thought I could handle it.
結果我錯了
But I was wrong.
要不是哈利和羅恩及時出現
If Harry and Ron hadn't come and found me,
我可能已經死了
I'd probably be dead.
即使是這樣  這也是件傻事
Be that as it may, it was an extremely foolish thing to do.
想不到你這麼冒失
I expected more rational behavior
太讓我失望了
and am very disappointed in you.
因為你嚴重的判斷失誤
Five points will be taken from Gryffindor
格蘭芬多扣掉5分
for your serious lack of judgment.
至於你們兩位先生
As for you two gentlemen.
要記住你們這次純屬走運
I just hope you realize how fortunate you are.
不是每個新生都能面對巨怪
Not many first-year students could take on a troll
全身而退的
and live to tell the tale.
每個人
Five points
各獎勵5分
will be awarded to each of you
算是為你們的狗屎運
for sheer dumb luck.
你們該走了  巨怪馬上就要醒了
Perhaps you ought to go. It might wake up.
再吃點麵包吧  哥們
Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on.
羅恩說得沒錯  今天你需要消耗體力
Ron's right. You'll need your strength today.
我不餓
I'm not hungry.
祝你今天好運  波特
Good luck today, Potter.
巨怪你都打敗了
You've proven yourself against a troll.
魁地奇比賽更是不在話下
A game of Quidditch should be easy work.
哪怕對手是斯萊特林
Even if it is against Slytherin.
-血跡是這麼回事  -血跡
- That explains the blood. - Blood?
我覺得昨晚斯內普用巨怪聲東擊西
Last night, I'm guessing Snape let the troll in as a diversion
乘機闖過守護犬
so he could get past that dog.
但被咬了  所以跛了
But he got bit, that's why he's limping.
他幹嘛要招惹三頭犬
But why would anyone go near that dog?
海格在古靈閣取出一件東西
At Gringotts, Hagrid took something out of the vault.
他說這是霍格沃茨的公事  高度機密
Said it was Hogwarts business, very secret.
你的意思是
You're saying...
那就是三頭犬守護的東西
That's what the dog's guarding.
斯內普想偷走
That's what Snape wants.
這麼早就送郵件嗎
Bit early for mail, isn't it?
都沒人給我寄過包裹呢
But I never get mail.
打開瞧瞧
Let's open it.
飛天掃帚
It's a broomstick.
這不是普通的飛天掃帚  哈利
That's not just a broomstick, Harry,
這可是光輪2000
it's a Nimbus 2000!
但這是誰...
But who...?
怕不怕  哈利
Scared, Harry?
一點點
A little.
很正常  我第一次上場也是這樣的
It's all right. I felt the same way before my first game.
後來呢
What happened?
記不清了
I don't really remember.
兩分鐘  我被遊走球擊中腦袋
I took a Bludger to the head two minutes in.
在醫院昏迷了一個星期
Woke up in hospital a week later.
大家好  歡迎觀看霍格沃茨本學期首場魁地奇比賽
Hello. Welcome to Hogwarts' first Quidditch game of the season.
今天的比賽  由斯萊特林對戰格蘭芬多
Today's game, Slytherin versus Gryffindor!
球員們各就各位
The players take their positions
霍奇夫人步入球場  宣佈比賽開始
as Madam Hooch steps onto the field to begin the game!
我希望今天的比賽
Now, I want a nice, clean game
公正  又精彩
from all of you!
遊走球升空了  緊跟著的是金色飛賊
The Bludgers are up, followed by the Golden Snitch.
記住  金色飛賊值150分
Remember, the Snitch is worth 150 points.
找球手逮住它  比賽就結束
The Seeker who catches the Snitch ends the game.
鬼飛球上天  比賽開始
The Quaffle is released and the game begins!
安吉麗娜·約翰遜進球  格蘭芬多得10分
Angelina Johnson scores! Ten points for Gryffindor!
漂亮
Well done!
斯萊特林得球
Slytherin takes the Quaffle.
布萊奇傳球給馬庫斯·弗林特隊長
Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
格蘭芬多再得10分
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
給我
Give me that!
搶佔那邊
Take that side!
哈利的掃帚怎麼回事
What's going on with Harry's broomstick?
斯內普在給掃帚下霉咒
It's Snape. He's jinxing the broom!
-真的嗎  那怎麼辦  -看我的
- Jinxing the broom? What do we do? - Leave it to me.
快點  赫敏
Come on, Hermione!
火焰熊熊
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
火  你身上著火了
Fire! You're on fire!
沖  沖  沖
Go, go, go, go!
他好像要吐了
Looks like he's gonna be sick.
他逮住金色飛賊了
He's got the Snitch!
哈利波特為隊伍贏得了150分
Harry Potter receives 150 points for catching the Snitch!
格蘭芬多勝出
Gryffindor wins!
別亂說  斯內普幹嘛要給哈利的掃帚下咒
Nonsense! Why would Snape put a curse on Harry's broom?
誰知道  他為什麼要惹三頭犬
Who knows? Why was he trying to get past that three-headed dog?
-誰告訴你們路威的  -路威
- Who told you about Fluffy? - Fluffy?
這個名字也有「毛球」的意思
那東西還有名字嗎
That thing has a name?
當然了  那可是我的寵物
Of course he has a name. He's mine.
我從愛爾蘭人手媔R下的
I bought him off an Irishman.
-用來給鄧布利多看守...  -什麼
- I lent him to Dumbledore to guard... - Yes?
我不該說的  夠了  不許再問了
Shouldn't have said that. No more questions! Don't ask any more question!
這是最高機密
That's top-secret.
不管路威在看守什麼
But whatever Fluffy's guarding,
那就是斯內普要偷的東西
Snape's trying to steal it.
胡說八道  斯內普教授可是霍格沃茨的老師
Codswallop. Professor Snape is a Hogwarts teacher.
誰知道  反正我看到他在下咒語
Hogwarts teacher or not, I know a spell when I see one.
我在書媗爸儦L
I've read all about them.
需要眼睛緊盯目標  斯內普就沒眨過眼
You've got to keep eye contact, and Snape wasn't blinking.
沒錯
Exactly.
你們三個聽我說
Now, you listen to me, all three of you.
這件事太危險
You're meddling in things
你們不該攙和
that ought not to be meddled in. It's dangerous.
狗狗看護的東西
What that dog is guarding
只和鄧布利多及尼古拉斯·勒梅有關
is between Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel.
尼古拉斯·勒梅
Nicholas Flamel?
糟糕  我又說漏嘴了
I shouldn't have said that. I should not have said that.
誰是尼古拉斯·勒梅
Nicholas Flamel. Who's Nicholas Flamel?
我不知道
I don't know.
聖誕快樂  聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas Merry Christmas
霍格沃茨的鐘聲響起
Ring the Hogwarts bell
聖誕快樂  聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas Merry Christmas
輕施一個聖誕魔法
Cast a Christmas spell
騎士  走E5
Knight to e5.
王后  走E5
Queen to e5.
太暴力了
That's totally barbaric!
巫師象棋就是這樣
That's wizard's chess.
你已經打包好行李了
I see you've packed.
你可沒有
I see you haven't.
計劃有變  我爸媽
Change of plans. My parents decided to
去羅馬尼亞看望我哥查理去了
go to Romania to visit my brother Charlie.
他在那堿膍s火龍
He's studying dragons there.
也好  你可以協助哈利
Good. You can help Harry.
他正在圖書館尋找尼古拉斯·勒梅的信息呢
He's going to the library to look up Nicholas Flamel.
我們都翻遍了  還是一無所獲
We've looked a hundred times!
別忘了還有禁書區
Not in the restricted section.
聖誕快樂
Happy Christmas.
我覺得咱們會被她帶壞的
I think we've had a bad influence on her.
哈利  醒醒  快來看  哈利
Harry, wake up! Come on, Harry, wake up!
聖誕快樂  哈利
Happy Christmas, Harry.
聖誕快樂  羅恩
Happy Christmas, Ron.
你穿的是什麼
What are you wearing?
媽媽織的毛衣  好像你也有一件
Oh, my mum made it. Looks like you've got one too.
-我的禮物  -是啊
- I've got presents? - Yeah.
就是這個
There they are.
「令尊過世前  把此物托付給我
"Your father left this in my possession before he died.
今物歸原主  請妥善使用」
It is time it was returned to you. Use it well. "
這是什麼東西
What is it?
像是斗篷
Some kind of cloak.
不錯  穿上瞧瞧
Well, let's see, then. Put it on.
我的身體不見了
My body's gone!
我知道了  這是件隱形斗篷
I know what that is. That's an invisibility cloak!
我隱形了
I'm invisible?
這可是稀有寶貝
They're really rare.
奇怪  誰寄給你的
I wonder who gave it to you.
沒有署名  只是寫著「請妥善使用」
There was no name. It just said, "Use it well. "
《著名的食火者》
Famous Fire-Eaters.
《十五世紀的惡魔》
Fifteenth-Century Fiends.
勒梅  尼古拉斯·勒梅  你在哪傜NFlamel. Nicholas Flamel. Where are you?
誰
Who's there?
我知道你在堶  躲不了的
I know you're in there. You can't hide.
是誰  快點現形
Who is it? Show yourself.
西弗勒斯  我...
Severus, I...
你不希望我和你對著干吧  奇洛
You don't want me as your enemy, Quirrell.
我不清楚你在說什麼
I don't know what you mean.
恰恰相反  你很清楚
You know perfectly well what I mean.
我們有空再聊
We'll have another little chat soon.
好好聊聊你究竟在替誰做事
When you've had time to decide where your loyalties lie.
教授們  我在禁書區發現了這個
Professors. I found this in the restricted section.
還燙手呢  顯然有學生溜出寢室了
It's still hot. That means there's a student out of bed.
我所顯示的不是你的臉  而是你心堛煽鰼潿N"I show not your face but your heart desire"
Erised stra ehru oyt ube cafru oyt on wohsi
媽媽
Mum?
爸爸
Dad?
羅恩  你得看看這個  一定得看看
Ron, you've really gotta see this! Ron, you've gotta see this!
羅恩  快點起床
Ron, Ron, come on, get out of bed!
-怎麼了  -有件東西你一定得看看
- Why? - There's something you've got to see! Come on.
快  快點  看  這是我父母
Come on! Come! Come look, it's my parents!
我只看到我們倆
I only see us.
對準角度再看  站這傜NLook in properly. Go on, stand there.
-看到了沒  -是我自己  成了學生會主席
- There. You see them, don't you? - That's me! Only I'm head boy.
而且贏了魁地奇杯
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
我的天吶  我還是魁地奇隊長
And bloody hell! I'm Quidditch captain too!
看上去帥呆了
I look good.
哈利  你覺得鏡子顯示的是未來麼
Harry, do you think this mirror shows the future?
怎麼可能  我父母都已經過世了
How can it? Both my parents are dead.
又來了嗎  哈利
Back again, Harry?
你和以前那些人一樣
I see that you, like so many before you
在厄奡腋]鏡中找到了樂趣
have discovered the delights of the Mirror of Erised.
我想現在你應該知道它的作用
I trust by now you realize what it does.
給你點提示
Let me give you a clue.
只有世上最快樂的人
The happiest man on earth
才會在鏡子中會看到
would look in the mirror and see only himself
現實中的自己
exactly as he is.
那麼  這是一面顯示我們欲求的鏡子
So then, it shows us what we want. Whatever we want.
是  也不是
Yes. And no.
它反映的其實是
It shows us nothing more or less
我們內心最最深切的渴望
than the deepest and most desperate desires of our hearts.
對於你  哈利  你從沒見過家人
Now you, Harry, who have never known your family.
所以看到了他們在你身邊
You see them standing beside you.
但記住  哈利
But remember this, Harry.
這塊鏡子不會給我們知識
This mirror gives us neither knowledge
和真相
or truth.
人們只會在它前面虛度光陰  甚至發瘋
Men have wasted away in front of it. Even gone mad.
所以我明天要把它挪個地方
That is why tomorrow it will be moved to a new home.
而且我告訴你
And I must ask you
不要想著找它了
not to go looking for it again.
人不能活在夢傜NIt does not do to dwell on dreams
而忘記生活
and forget to live.
我讓你們找錯了地方
I had you looking in the wrong section.
我怎麼會那麼笨呢
How could I be so stupid?
幾周前我接了這本書解解悶
I checked this out weeks ago for a bit of light reading.
這能解悶嗎
This is light?
沒錯  就是這個
Of course! Here it is!
尼古拉斯·勒梅是
Nicholas Flamel is the
唯一已知的魔法石製作者
only known maker of the Philosopher's Stone.
什麼東西
The what?
難道你們倆從來不看書嗎
Honestly, don't you two read?
魔法石
"The Philosopher's Stone
是一種具有超凡魔力的傳奇物品
is a legendary substance with astonishing powers.
它可以點石成金
It'll transform any metal into pure gold,
還能製作長生不老藥
and produces the Elixir of Life
讓人永生
which will make the drinker immortal. "
-長生不老  -就是說你死不了
- Immortal? - It means you'll never die.
我知道是什麼意思
I know what it means!
「現存的唯一魔法石
"The only Stone currently in existence
歸尼古拉斯·勒梅先生所有
belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel,
這位著名的煉金術士
the noted alchemist who last year
去年度過了他的第665個生日」
celebrated his 665th birthday."
路威在三樓守護的就是這東西
That's what Fluffy's guarding on the third floor.
那活板門堶探N是這個  魔法石
That's what's under the trap door. The Philosopher's Stone.
-海格  -你好
- Hagrid. - Oh, hello.
抱歉  無意冒犯
Sorry, don't wish to be rude,
但是今天我不能陪你們玩了
but I'm in no fit state to entertain today.
我們知道魔法石的事了
We know about the Philosopher's Stone.
我們認為斯內普想偷它
We think Snape's trying to steal it.
斯內普  你們不會還在懷疑他吧
Snape? Come on, are you still on about him, aren't you?
海格  我們知道他想得到魔法石
Hagrid, we know he's after the stone,
只是不知道什麼目
we just don't know why.
斯內普是保護魔法石的老師之一
Snape is one of the teachers protecting the Stone.
他不會去偷它的
He's not about to steal it.
什麼
What?
沒錯  你們快走吧  我今天有點忙
You heard. Alright, come on now, I'm a bit preoccupied today.
等等  「老師之一」
Wait a minute. "One of the teachers"?
這就對了
Of course!
還有其他東西在保護著魔法石  對吧
There are other things defending the Stone, aren't there?
-咒語和魔法  -沒錯
- Spells, enchantments. - That's right.
要我說簡直是浪費時間
Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
沒有人能過得了路威這一關
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
誰都不知道方法  除了我和鄧布利多
Ain't a soul knows how, except for me and Dumbledore.
我不該告訴你們的  我不該多嘴的
I shouldn't have told you that. I should not have told you that.
海格  那到底是什麼
Hagrid, what exactly is that?
那個嗎  是個  是個
That? It's a...it's um...
我知道那是什麼
I know what that is!
但是海格  你是怎麼弄到的
But, Hagrid, how did you get one?
我從酒吧堛漱@個陌生人那媊麂茠暝NI won it. Off a stranger I met down at the pub.
說實話  那人好像巴不得送走它
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it, as a matter of fact.
那是
Is that...
一條龍嗎
a dragon?
那可不是普通的龍
That's not just a dragon.
那是一條挪威脊背龍
That's a Norwegian Ridgeback.
我哥哥查理就在羅馬尼亞研究它們
My brother Charlie works with these in Romania.
不覺得他很漂亮嗎  上帝保佑他
Isn't he beautiful? Oh, bless him.
快看  找媽媽來了
Look, he knows his mummy.
你好  諾伯
Hello, Norbert.
諾伯
Norbert?
對啊  他總得有個名字吧
Yeah, well, he's gotta have a name, don't he?
對吧  諾伯
Don't you, Norbert?
當然了  他還是有點缺乏教養
He'll have to be trained up a bit, of course.
那是誰
Who's that?
馬爾福
Malfoy.
不好了
Oh, dear.
海格一直想養一條龍
Hagrid always wanted a dragon.
第一次見到我的時候就跟我說過
Told me so the first time I ever met him.
這太瘋狂了  更糟的是  馬爾福知道了
It's crazy. And worse, Malfoy knows.
-我不明白  是壞事嗎  -是的
- I don't understand. Is that bad? - It's bad.
晚安
Good evening.
無論如何  我重複  無論如何
Nothing, I repeat, nothing...
學生都不能半夜埵b學校媔４}
gives a student the right to walk about the school at night.
因此  作為對你們的懲罰
Therefore, as punishment for your actions,
扣掉50分
50 points will be taken.
-50分  -每個人
-50?! - Each.
為了確保這種事不再發生
And to ensure it doesn't happen again,
你們四個都要留堂
all four of you will receive detention.
抱歉  教授  也許我聽錯了
Excuse me, professor, perhaps I heard you wrong.
你剛說我們四個
I thought you said the four of us.
不  我就是那麼說的  馬爾福先生
No, you heard me correctly, Mr Malfoy.
儘管你的出發點是好的
You see, honorable as your intentions were,
但是你也半夜跑出來了
but you too were out of bed after hours.
你要跟你的同學們一起受罰
You will join your classmates in detention.
以前的懲罰方式廢除了  真可惜
A pity they let the old punishments die.
以前被罰留堂的人
There was a time detention would found you
都要倒掛在地牢傜Nhanging by your thumbs in the dungeons.
我真懷念那慘叫聲
God, I miss the screaming.
今晚你們和海格一起留堂
You'll be serving detention with Hagrid tonight.
他要到禁林媬嚍I事情
He's got a little job to do inside the Dark Forest.
調皮蟲們來了  海格
A sorry lot, this, Hagrid.
天啊  夥計
Oh, good God, man.
你還在對那條龍念念不忘嗎
You're not still on about that bloody dragon, are you?
諾伯走了
Norbert's gone.
鄧布利多把他送到羅馬尼亞的棲息地了
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania to live in a colony.
那是好事  不是嗎
Well, that's good, isn't it?
他能和同類在一起了
He'll be with his own kind.
萬一他不喜歡羅馬尼亞呢
Yeah, but what if he don't like Romania?
如果其他的龍欺負他怎麼辦
What if the other dragons are mean to him?
他畢竟才那麼小
He's only a baby after all.
得了吧  振作起來
Oh for God's sake, pulI yourself together, man.
你要進林子堨h的
You're going into the Forest after all.
頭腦最好保持清醒
Got to have your wits about you.
禁林  我以為你在開玩笑
The Forest? I thought that was a joke.
我們不能進去
We can't go in there.
學生不准進去的
Students aren't allowed.
而且堶惘許NAnd there are...
狼人
werewolves.
那林子堨i不止有狼人
Oh, there's more than werewolves in those trees, eh.
這點可以肯定
You can be sure of that.
晚安
Nighty-night.
好了  我們走吧
Right. Let's go.
海格  那是什麼
Hagrid, what is that?
我們來的目的  看到了嗎
What we're here for. See that?
那是獨角獸的血
That's unicorn blood, that is.
幾星期前我發現有一頭死掉了
I found one dead a few weeks ago.
這一頭傷得很重
Now, this one's been hurt bad by something.
我們的任務
So, it's our job
就是找到那可憐的傢伙
to go and find the poor beast.
羅恩  赫敏  你們跟著我
Ron, Hermione, you come with me.
好的
Ok.
哈利  你跟馬爾福一起
Harry, you'll go with Malfoy.
好吧  那我要牙牙
Okay. Then I get Fang.
行  要知道  他膽小的很
Fine. Just so you know, he's a bloody coward.
我回去告訴我爸  走著瞧
You wait till my father hears about this.
這是僕人幹的活
This is servant's stuff.
也許我看錯了  德拉科
If I didn't know better, Draco,
你是不是害怕了
I'd say you were scared.
我才不害怕  波特
I'm not scared,  Potter.
你聽到了嗎
Do you hear that?
來吧  牙牙
Come on, Fang.
說我害怕
Scared!
怎麼了  牙牙
What is it, Fang?
哈利·波特  你必須離開這傜NHarry Potter, you must leave.
這堳雃h生物都認識你
You are known to many creatures here.
這時候的禁林不安全  尤其對於你來說
The Forest is not safe at this time. Especially for you.
你趕走的那個是什麼東西
But what was that thing you saved me from?
一個怪物
A monstrous creature.
屠殺獨角獸是很可怕的罪行
It is a terrible crime to slay an unicorn.
喝了獨角獸的血會延續你的生命
Drinking the blood of an unicorn will keep you alive
即使你已經茍延殘喘
even if you are an inch from death.
但是要付出很大的代價
But at a terrible price.
殺掉這麼純潔的生物
For you have slain something so pure
從它的血液碰到你嘴唇的那一刻起
that from the moment the blood touches your lips,
你就半生半死了
you will have a half-life.
一輩子被詛咒
A cursed life.
但是誰會選擇這樣活著
But who would choose such a life?
你想不到嗎
Can you think of no one?
你的意思是殺了這獨角獸的
Do you mean to say that thing that killed the unicorn...
那個喝了它的血的
that was drinking its blood,
是伏地魔嗎
that was Voldemort?
你知道此時此刻在學校傜NDo you know what is hidden in the school
藏著什麼東西嗎  波特先生
at this very moment, Mr. Potter?
魔法石
The Philosopher's Stone.
哈利
Harry!
你好啊  費倫澤
Hello there, Firenze.
看來你見過波特了
See you've met our young Mr. Potter.
你還好吧  哈利
You all right there, Harry?
哈利·波特  我就送你到這傜NHarry Potter, this is where I leave you.
你現在安全了  祝你好運
You're safe now. Good luck.
你是說  神秘人在禁林媔鄃NYou mean, You-Know-Who is out there right now in the Forest?
他很虛弱  靠喝獨角獸的血為生
But he's weak. He's living off the unicorns.
你不明白嗎  我們之前錯了
Don't you see? We had it wrong.
斯內普偷魔法石不是為了自己
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself.
他是為伏地魔偷的
He wants the stone for Voldemort.
有了長生不老藥  伏地魔就能再次崛起
With the Elixir of Life, Voldemort will be strong again.
他會
He'll...
他會回歸的
He'll come back.
但是如果他回歸了
But if he comes back,
他是不是要來殺了你
you don't think he'll try to kill you, do you?
如果他有機會  也許今晚就動手了
If he'd had the chance, he might have tried tonight.
我還擔心魔藥課期末考呢
And to think I've been worrying about my Potions final.
等等  我們忘記了一點
Hang on a minute. We're forgetting one thing.
伏地魔唯一害怕的人是誰
Who's the one wizard Voldemort always feared?
鄧布利多
Dumbledore.
只要鄧布利多在這  哈利  你就是安全的
As long as Dumbledore is around, Harry, you're safe.
只要鄧布利多在這  沒有人傷得了你
As long as Dumbledore is around, you can't be touched.
我一直以為霍格沃茨的期末考很難
I'd always heard Hogwarts' end-of-year exams were frightful,
但是卻覺得挺輕鬆的
but I found that rather enjoyable.
那是你  你還好吧  哈利
Speak for yourself. All right there, Harry?
我的傷疤  一直在灼燒
My scar. It keeps burning.
之前也發生過
It's happened before.
這次不一樣了
Not like this.
也許你該去校醫院看一下
Perhaps you should see the nurse.
我想這是個警告  危險要到來了
I think it's a warning. It means danger's coming.
-這就對了  -怎麼了
- Of course! - What is it?
你不覺得有點奇怪嗎
Don't you think it's a bit odd
海格最渴望的東西就是一條龍
that what Hagrid wants more than anything is a dragon,
結果剛好那個陌生人就有一條
and a stranger turns up who just happens to have one?
有多少人會揣著龍蛋
I mean, how many people wander around
四處溜躂
with dragon eggs in their pocket?
我之前怎麼就沒想明白呢
Why didn't I see it before?
海格  那龍蛋是誰給你的
Hagrid, who gave you the dragon egg?
他長的什麼樣
What did he look like?
我不知道  一直沒看到他的臉
I don't know, I never saw his face.
他戴著兜帽
He kept his hood up.
那個陌生人  你們肯定談過話
This stanger though, you and he must have talked.
他想知道我養過哪些生物
Well, he wanted to know what sort of creatures I looked after.
我跟他說  我說  「養過路威
I told him, I said, "After Fluffy,
養一條龍簡直是小意思」
a dragon's gonna be no problem."
那他對路威感興趣嗎
Then is he interested in Fluffy?
他當然對路威感興趣
Well, of course he was interested in Fluffy.
有多少人見過三頭犬
How often do you come across a three-headed dog?
哪怕你是倒賣這個的
Even if you were in the trade.
但是我跟他說  我說  我說
But I told him, I said, I said that
「對待生物的訣竅
"The trick with any beast
就是要安撫它」
is to know how to calm him."
拿路威說吧
Take Fluffy, for example.
給他來點音樂他就睡著了
Just play him a little bit of music and he falls straight to sleep.
我不該告訴你們
I shouldn't have told you that.
你們要去哪  等等
Where are you going? Wait!
我們要見鄧布利多教授  馬上
We have to see professor Dumbledore. Immediately!
鄧布利多教授不在這傜NI'm afraid professor Dumbledore is not here.
魔法部有點緊急的事情
He received an urgent owl from the Ministry of Magic
他去倫敦了
and left immediately for London.
他走了  但是這事很重要
He's gone? But this is important!
這事有關魔法石
This is about the Philosopher's Stone!
-你怎麼知道  -有人想去偷了它
- How do you know...? - Someone's going to try and steal it.
我不知道你們三個是怎麼知道魔法石的
I don't know how you three found out about the Stone,
但是我保證它現在很安全
but I assure you it is perfectly well protected.
你們回宿舍去吧  安靜點走
Now would you go back to your dormitories? Quietly.
海格碰到的不是陌生人  對吧
That was no stranger Hagrid have met, isn't it?
是斯內普
It was Snape.
也就是說他知道怎麼繞過路威了
Which means he knows how to get past Fluffy.
-而且鄧布利多不在  -下午好
- And with Dumbledore gone... - Good afternoon.
這麼好的天氣  你們三個小格蘭芬多
Now, what would three young Gryffindors such as yourselves
在室內待著幹什麼呢
be doing inside on a day like this?
-我們只是  -你們要小心點
- We were just... - You ought to be careful.
別人會以為你們
People will think you're...
圖謀不軌
up to something.
我們該怎麼辦
Now what do we do?
我們穿越活板門  就今晚
We go down the trap door. Tonight.
萊福
Trevor.
萊福  走開  你怎麼在這
Trevor, go! You shouldn't be here!
你們怎麼在這
Neither should you.
你們又要偷偷溜出去  對吧
You're sneaking out again, aren't you?
納威  聽著  我們
Now, Neville, listen. We were...
不  我不會放你們走的
No, I won't let you!
你們又會給格蘭芬多帶來麻煩的
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble again.
我跟你們拼了
I'll fight you.
納威  我很抱歉
Neville, I'm really really sorry about this.
統統石化
Petrificus Totalus.
你有時候挺嚇人的  你知道嗎
You're a little scary sometimes, you know that?
很棒  但是也挺嚇人
Brilliant, but scary.
我們走吧
Let's go.
-對不起  -這是為了你好
- Sorry. - It's for your own good, you know.
你踩到我的腳了
You stood on my foot!
對不起
Sorry.
阿拉霍洞開
Alohomora.
等等  他在
Wait a minute. He's...
打呼嚕
snoring.
斯內普已經來了
Snape's already been here.
他對這豎琴施了咒語
He's put a spell on the harp.
它的口臭真重
It's got horrible breath.
-我們得把它的爪子挪開  -什麼
- We have to move its paw. - What?
來吧
Come on!
好了  推一把
Okay. Push.
我先進去  等我給你們信號再下去
I'll go first. Don't follow until I give you a sign.
如果遇到了麻煩  你們就趕緊離開
If something bad happens, get yourselves out.
你們覺不覺得有點安靜
Does it seem a bit quiet to you?
豎琴
The harp.
它停止彈奏了
It's stopped playing.
快跳
Jump!
幸好有這種植物在
Lucky this plant thing's here, really.
別動  你們倆  這是魔鬼之網
Stop moving, both of you. This is Devil's Snare.
你們必須要放鬆  不然的話
You have to relax. If you don't,
你會死得更快
it will only kill you faster.
死得更快  這叫我怎麼放鬆
Kill us faster? Oh, now I can relax!
赫敏
Hermione!
-我們該怎麼辦  -放鬆
- Now what are we gonna do? - Just relax!
赫敏  你在哪傜NHermione, where are you?
按我說的做  相信我
Do what I say! Trust me.
-你沒事吧  -沒事  我還好
- Are you okay? - Yeah, I'm fine.
-他還是沒放鬆  是吧  -顯然是
- He's not relaxing, is he? - Apparently not.
-我們得想想辦法  -什麼辦法
- We've gotta do something. - What?
草藥課上好像讀到過
I remember reading something in Herbology.
魔鬼網  魔鬼網  魔網致命
Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare. It's deadly fun
卻怕太陽  沒錯  它怕陽光
but will sulk in the sun! That's it! Devil's Snare hates sunlight.
明亮如晝
Lumus Solem.
-羅恩  你還好吧  -還好
- Ron, you okay? - Yeah.
幸好沒有慌張
Lucky we didn't panic.
幸好赫敏草藥課聽講了
Lucky Hermione pays attention in Herbology.
什麼聲音
What is that?
不知道  像是翅膀的聲音
I don't know. Sounds like wings.
奇怪  我從來沒見過這種鳥
Curious. I've never seen birds like these.
那不是鳥  是鑰匙
They're not birds. They're keys.
肯定有一把是開那扇門的
And I'll bet one of them fits that door.
-我們要怎麼辦  -我不知道
- What's this all about? - I don't know.
奇怪
Strange.
阿拉霍洞開
Alohomora!
試試總沒錯吧
Well, it was worth a try.
怎麼辦  有上千把鑰匙呢
What will we do? There must be a thousand keys.
我們要找一把古色古香的大鑰匙
We want a big, old-fashioned one.
像把手一樣  可能生蚺F
Probably rusty like the handle.
我看到了  翅膀受傷的那把
I see it! The one with the broken wing.
怎麼了  哈利
What's wrong, Harry?
這太簡單了
It's too simple.
加油  哈利
Go on, Harry!
如果斯內普都能騎著舊掃帚抓住它
If Snape could catch it on that old broomstick,
那你也能
you can.
你可是一個世紀以來最年輕的找球手
You're the youngest Seeker in a century.
看來沒那麼簡單
This complicates things a bit.
接住鑰匙
Catch the key!
快點
Hurry up!
我不喜歡這  一點也不喜歡
I don't like this. I don't like this at all.
我們在哪  墓地嗎
Where are we? A graveyard.
這不是墓地
This is no graveyard.
這是個棋盤
It's a chessboard.
門在那邊
There's the door.
現在我們怎麼辦
Now what do we do?
這還不明顯嗎
It's obvious, isn't it?
我們得下棋才能走到屋子的那邊
We've got to play our way across the room.
好吧  哈利  你去那個主教的位置[就是相]
Alright, Harry, you take the empty bishop's square.
赫敏  你當皇后邊上的車
Hermione, you'll be the queen-side castle.
至於我  我要做個騎士[也就是馬]
As for me, I'll be a knight.
然後呢
What happens now?
白棋先走
Well, white moves first.
然後
And then
看我們的
we play.
羅恩  我們不會是要
Ron, you don't suppose this is going to be like
下真正的巫師棋吧  是嗎
real wizard's chess, do you?
你  走到D5
You there, d5.
是的  赫敏
Yes, Hermione.
這和巫師棋一模一樣
I think this is gonna be exactly like wizard's chess.
車到E4
Castle to e4!
卒到C3
Pawn to c3!
-等等  -沒錯  哈利
- Wait a minute. - You understand right, Harry.
我走完下一步  皇后會吃掉我
Once I make my move, the queen will take me.
你就可以把國王將死了
Then you're free to check the king.
-不  羅恩  不  -什麼意思
- No. Ron, no! - What is it?
他要犧牲自己
He's going to sacrifice himself.
不行  一定還有別的辦法
No, you can't, there must be another way!
你到底想不想阻止斯內普偷魔法石
Do you wanna stop Snape from getting that Stone or not?
哈利  你一定要繼續下去  我知道
Harry, it's you that has to go on. I know it.
不是我  也不是赫敏  是你
Not me. Not Hermione. You.
馬去H3
Knight to h3.
將軍
Check.
羅恩
Ron!
不  別動
No, don't move!
別忘了  棋局還沒結束
Don't forget, we're still playing.
將軍
Checkmate.
照看好羅恩  然後去貓頭鷹棚屋
Take care of Ron. Then go to the owlery.
給鄧布利多送信  羅恩說得對
Send a message to Dumbledore. Ron's right.
我得繼續
I have to go on.
你會沒事的  哈利
You'll be okay, Harry.
你是個了不起的巫師  真的
You're a great wizard. You really are.
不如你出色
Not as good as you.
我  不過是死讀書  再耍點小聰明
Me? Books and cleverness.
還有更重要的東西
There are more important things.
那就是友誼和勇氣
Friendship and bravery.
哈利  你要小心
And, Harry, just be careful.
是你?
You?
不  不可能  斯內普  是他...
No, it can't be. Snape, he was the...
是啊  他確實像個壞人  不是嗎
Yes, he does seem the type, doesn't he?
有他在  誰還會懷疑
Next to him, who would suspect
可憐的  結結巴巴的奇洛教授
poor, stuttering Professor Quirrell?
但是那天  魁地奇比賽上
But that day, during the Quidditch match,
斯內普想殺了我
Snape tried to kill me.
不  親愛的  是我要殺你
No, dear boy. I tried to kill you!
相信我  要不是斯內普的斗篷著火了
And trust me, if Snape's cloak hadn't caught fire
把我撞翻了
and broken my eye contact
我本可以成功的
I would have succeeded.
斯內普再念反咒也沒用
Even with Snape muttering his little countercurse.
斯內普是在救我嗎
Snape was trying to save me?
我從一開始就知道你對我是個威脅
I knew you were a danger to me right from the off,
尤其是萬聖節後
especially after Halloween.
是你把巨怪放進來的
Then you let the troll in!
非常好  波特  是的
Very good, Potter, yes.
倒霉的是  斯內普起了疑心
Snape, unfortunately, wasn't fooled.
人們都跑向地牢時
While everyone was running about the dongeon,
他直接趕到四樓阻攔我
he went to the third floor to head me off.
當然  他再也不相信我了
He, of course, never trusted me again.
他很少讓我單獨一人  但是他不知道
He rarely left me alone. But he doesn't understand.
我從來都不是一個人  不是
I'm never alone. Never.
這面鏡子是怎麼回事
Now, what does this mirror do?
我看到了我的渴望
I see what I desire.
我看到我拿著魔法石
I see myself holding the Stone.
但我是怎麼得到的呢
But how do I get it?
利用那個男孩
Use the boy.
過來  波特  快點
Come here, Potter! Now!
告訴我  你看到了什麼
Tell me, what do you see?
怎麼樣  你看到了什麼
What is it? What do you see?
我正在跟鄧布利多握手
I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore.
我贏得了學院杯
I've won the house cup.
他在說謊
He lies.
說實話  你看到了什麼
Tell the truth! What do you see?
讓我跟他說
Let me speak to him.
主人  你的體力還不夠
Master, you are not strong enough.
這點力氣還是有的
I have strength enough for this.
哈利·波特
Harry Potter
我們又見面了
we meet again.
伏地魔
Voldemort.
是啊  你看我變成什麼樣子了
Yes. You see what I've become?
看我怎樣茍延殘喘
See what I must do to survive?
活在別人的身體  當個寄生蟲
Live off another. A mere parasite.
獨角獸的血給了我些體力
Unicorn blood can sustain me
卻不能給我軀體
but it cannot give me a body of my own.
但是有一樣東西可以
But there is something that can.
那東西  正好就在你的口袋傜NSomething that, conveniently enough, lies in your pocket.
攔住他
Stop him!
別犯傻了
Don't be a fool.
何苦自尋死路
Why suffer an horrific death
不如共享永生
when you can join me and live?
休想
Never!
勇氣可嘉  你父母也是如此
Bravery. Your parents had it too.
告訴我  哈利
Tell me, Harry
你想不想再見到你的父母
would you like to see your mother and father again?
我們聯手
Together
可以讓他們起死回生
we can bring them back.
我只要一點點回報
All I ask is for something in return.
沒錯  哈利
That's it, Harry.
世上本無善惡
There is no good and evil.
只有權力
There is only power
和無力追逐權力的人
and those too weak to seek it.
我們聯手  可以成就大事
Together, we'll do extraordinary things.
把魔法石給我
Just give me the Stone!
你撒謊
You liar!
殺了他
Kill him!
這是什麼魔法
What is this magic?
蠢貨  快去搶魔法石
Fool, get the Stone!
下午好  哈利
Good afternoon, Harry.
-崇拜者的禮物?  -崇拜者?
- Tokens from your admirers? - Admirers?
你和奇洛教授
What happened in the dungeons
在地下室堛漪G事  是個秘密
between you and Professor Quirrell is a complete secret.
秘密總是不脛而走  全校都知道了
So, naturally, the whole school knows.
看來你的朋友羅恩
I see that your friend Ronald has saved you
幫你打開了巧克力蛙
the trouble of opening your Chocolate Frogs.
羅恩來過嗎  他還好嗎  赫敏呢
Ron was here? Is he all right? What about Hermione?
很好  他們都很好
Fine. They're both just fine.
-魔法石呢  -放鬆  親愛的
- What happened to the Stone? - Relax, dear boy.
魔法石已經被毀掉了
The Stone has been destroyed.
我和朋友尼可談了談
My friend Nicholas and I have had a little chat
一致認為這樣最好
and agreed it was best all around.
但那樣的話  勒梅會死的  不是嗎
But then, Flamel, he'll die, won't he?
他有足夠的長生不老藥來料理後事
He has enough Elixir to set his affairs in order.
但是  他會死
But yes, he will die.
我是怎麼拿到魔法石的  先生
How is it I got the Stone, sir?
我一看那面鏡子...
One minute I was staring in the mirror and...
你看  必須是
You see, only a person
想要找到魔法石  找到它
who wanted to find the Stone, find it
但不利用它的人  才能得到它
but not use it, would be able to get it.
這是我的妙計之一
That is one of my more brilliant ideas.
別跟別人說  我的妙計厲害吧
And between you and me, that is saying something.
是不是說  魔法石被毀掉了
Does that mean, with the Stone gone,
伏地魔就永遠消失了
that Voldemort can never come back?
恐怕
I'm afraid
他還會想辦法捲土重來
there are ways in which he can return.
哈利  你知道為什麼
Harry, do you know why
奇洛教授不能讓你碰他嗎
Professor Quirrell couldn't bear to have you touch him?
因為你的母親  她為你犧牲了自己
It was because of your mother. She sacrificed herself for you.
那種犧牲留下了印記
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
不  是看不見的印記
No, this kind of mark cannot be seen.
-在你的身體  -那是什麼
- It lives in your very skin. - What is it?
愛  哈利  是愛
Love, Harry. Love.
比比多味豆
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
我年輕時真倒霉
I was most unfortunate in my youth
吃到了顆嘔吐味的
to come across a vomit-flavored one.
從那以後  我就不喜歡豆子了
And since then, I'm afraid I've lost my liking for them.
不過我想  來一顆太妃糖味的
But I think I could be safe
總沒問題
with a nice toffee.
倒霉
Alas!
耳屎味
Earwax.
-還好吧  羅恩  -還好  你呢
- All right there, Ron? - All right. You?
很好  赫敏呢
All right. Hermione?
再好不過了
Never better.
又一年過去了
Another year gone.
沒記錯的話  現在要頒發學院杯
And now, as I understand it, the house cup needs awarding.
得分情況為
And the points stand thus:
第四名  格蘭芬多  312分
In fourth place, Gryffindor with 312 points.
第三名  赫奇帕奇  352分
Third place, Hufflepuff with 352 points.
第二名
In second place
拉文克勞  426分
Ravenclaw with 426 points.
第一名的是
And in first place
472分的斯萊特林學院
with 472 points, Slytherin house.
幹得好  夥計
Nice one, mate.
是啊  表現很好  斯萊特林  很好
Yes, well done, Slytherin. Well done.
然而  最近發生的幾件事也要計算在內
However, recent events must be taken into account.
我最後還要獎勵一些分數
And I have a few last-minute points to award.
赫敏·格蘭傑小姐
To Miss Hermione Granger,
當大家身處險境時
for the cool use of intellect
你冷靜思考
while others were in grave peril
獎勵50分
50 points.
做得好
Good job.
第二項  給羅恩·韋斯萊先生
Second, to Mr. Ronald Weasley,
因為你贏下了霍格沃茨
for the best-played game of chess
許多年來最精彩的一盤棋
that Hogwarts has seen these many years,
獎勵50分
50 points.
第三項
And third
哈利·波特先生
to Mr. Harry Potter
為你無畏的膽量和過人的勇氣
for pure nerve and outstanding courage
我要獎勵給格蘭芬多學院60分
I award Gryffindor house 60 points.
我們和斯萊特林打平了
We're tied with Slytherin!
最後還有  對付敵人
Finally, it takes a great deal of bravery
我們需要很大的勇氣
to stand up to your enemies
但在朋友面前堅定立場
but a great deal more
需要更大的勇氣
to stand up to your friends.
我要獎勵10分
I award 10 points
給納威·隆巴頓先生
to Neville Longbottom.
如果我沒算錯的話
Assuming that my calculations are correct
我覺得這堛爾佴Ⅲ搨n改變一下
I believe that a change of decoration is in order.
格蘭芬多贏得了學院杯
Gryffindor wins the house cup.
快走  快點  該遲到了
Come on, now. Hurry up, you'll be late.
火車就要開了  快走  快點
Train's leaving. Go on. Come on, hurry up.
-走吧  哈利  -等一下
- Come on, Harry. - One minute.
還以為你不告別就要走了呢
Thought you were leaving without saying goodbye, did you?
這個給你
This is for you.
謝謝  海格
Thanks, Hagrid.
走吧  走吧  記著  哈利
Go on. On with you. On with you now. Oh, listen, Harry.
要是你那個蠢貨表哥達力欺負你
If that dolt of a cousin of yours, Dudley, gives you any grief
你就威脅他
you could always threaten him
給他變一副豬耳朵  配他的尾巴
with a nice pair of ears to go with that tail of his.
但是海格  我們離開霍格沃茨
But Hagrid, we're not allowed to do magic
是不能施魔法的  你知道的
away from Hogwarts. You know that.
我知道  但是你的表哥不知道  對吧
I do. But your cousin don't, do he? Right?
回家的感覺有點奇怪  不是嗎
Feels strange to be going home, doesn't it?
我不是回家
I'm not going home.
不算是
Not really.